<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Post>
  <Id>4bb2b9af92c7417eb717f70c26d39e28</Id>
  <Title>There are no shortcuts to hiring the 'hard-to-hire'</Title>
  <Body>People who are in high demand - as almost all good software developers, data scientists and infrastructure engineers are - they do not behave like 'job seekers'. If you set up your recruitment process / system / methods on the idea that they are job seekers, you're going to have a tough time. In IT, a combination of rapidly changing markets, high demand for and short supply of talent means thousands of open, unfilled roles are costing companies -- and the economy -- money every day. For example, only in the US, the value of the approximately 263,586 unfilled IT jobs posted by employers adds up to $20.1 billion.


Stockholm is the home of billion dollar startups in Europe, and by one measure the Swedish capital is second only to Silicon Valley as the birthplace for the world's most successful internet companies.
On a per capita basis, Stockholm has 6.3 billion-dollar companies per million people (compared to the Valley with 6.9)


The Swedish start-up scene has shown incredible energy over the past few years as Stockholm became one of the hottest tech hubs on the planet. Five companies exemplify this surge: Spotify, Skype, Mojang, King and Klarna. These “unicorns” – the name given to start-ups worth more than a billion dollars – have all come out of 'Little Sweden' and it sure has inspired a new generation of entrepreneurs who now dream of achieving worldwide success.

**Fun fact:**


`The Nordic region alone, representing only 0.3 percent of the world’s population, makes up for 33 percent of the planet’s billion dollar exits.`





If your interested in learning more about tech recruitment,  or if you're looking to stay up-to-date with the latest trends in recruitment as well as technology - this blog is for you.

:::img-center
![ON-BR621_Unicor_DV_20160503135343.jpg](/Uploads/ON-BR621_Unicor_DV_20160503135343.jpg)
:::
.


</Body>
  <PubDate>2017-11-16T21:33:03.9714170+01:00</PubDate>
  <LastModified>2017-11-16T22:45:36.9650809+01:00</LastModified>
  <IsPublic>True</IsPublic>
  <IsDeleted>False</IsDeleted>
  <Comments />
</Post>